<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<record_update>
  <record table="x_snc_hack4good_0_hack4good_proposal" action="insert" sys_id="a1b2c3d4e5f67890a1b2c3d4e5f67890">
    <name>SafeSpace – AI-Powered Workplace Harassment Reporting & Prevention Platform</name>
    <short_description>Anonymous, AI-driven ServiceNow platform to report, manage, and prevent workplace harassment and misconduct.</short_description>
    <description><![CDATA[
Proposal Title: SafeSpace – AI-Powered Workplace Harassment Reporting & Prevention Platform

Summary:
SafeSpace is a ServiceNow-based secure platform designed to help employees report workplace harassment and misconduct confidentially. It leverages AI-driven categorization, automated workflows, and analytics to ensure fair, private, and timely resolutions.

Problem:
Workplace harassment often goes unreported due to fear of retaliation, stigma, or lack of trusted reporting mechanisms. Organizations struggle to maintain transparency, fairness, and confidentiality in handling such cases.

Solution:
SafeSpace empowers employees to report incidents anonymously and enables HR and compliance teams to investigate efficiently while maintaining privacy and data protection.

Key Features:
1. Anonymous Reporting Portal – Employees can submit confidential reports via chatbot, email, or form.
2. AI-Powered Case Categorization – Natural Language Processing (NLP) identifies the type and severity of reports.
3. Secure Escalation Workflow – Routes cases to designated HR or ethics officers with controlled access.
4. Sentiment & Trend Analysis – Detects emerging risk patterns or culture issues.
5. Resource & Support Library – Provides access to legal rights, counseling, and mental health help.
6. Confidential Analytics Dashboard – Visualizes trends without exposing identities.

Target Users:
- Corporates and HR Departments
- Compliance & Ethics Teams
- NGOs focused on employee welfare
- Government and public offices

Integrations:
- Microsoft Teams / Slack
- Twilio / WhatsApp
- ServiceNow Predictive Intelligence
- External Legal and Counseling APIs

Impact:
- Encourages safe and transparent workplaces
- Reduces fear of retaliation for victims
- Enhances HR efficiency and compliance tracking
- Promotes data-driven cultural change

Tech Stack:
- ServiceNow App Engine
- Flow Designer & IntegrationHub
- Virtual Agent + NLP
- Predictive Intelligence
- Performance Analytics

Estimated Effort (MVP):
- 7–9 weeks for reporting, triage, and analytics
- +3 weeks for integrations and trend detection

Author:
Hacktoberfest Contributor
Contact: placeholder@example.com

License:
MIT
]]></description>
    <author>Hacktoberfest Contributor</author>
    <category>Workplace Safety & Ethics</category>
    <impact_statement>Foster safer, more inclusive workplaces through AI-powered anonymous reporting, fair investigations, and proactive risk detection.</impact_statement>
    <features>Anonymous Reporting;AI Categorization;Secure Workflow;Trend Analysis;Resource Library;Confidential Dashboard</features>
    <target_users>Corporates, HR teams, NGOs, public offices</target_users>
    <integrations>Teams;Slack;Twilio;WhatsApp;Legal & Counseling APIs</integrations>
    <estimated_effort>MVP: 7–9 weeks</estimated_effort>
    <license>MIT</license>
    <sys_created_on>2025-10-31 00:00:00</sys_created_on>
  </record>
</record_update>
