<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<record_update>
<x_snc_hack4good_0_hack4good_proposal action="INSERT_OR_UPDATE">
<project_name>EcoTrack – Smart Sustainability Dashboard</project_name>
<focus_area>environment</focus_area>
<problem_statement>
Urban areas generate massive amounts of waste and carbon emissions daily.
Citizens lack accessible insights into how their actions impact the environment.
Local authorities and communities struggle to measure sustainability efforts effectively.
There’s a need for a transparent, data-driven platform that encourages eco-friendly behavior.
</problem_statement>
<proposed_solution>
EcoTrack is a web-based sustainability dashboard that helps users and communities track their environmental footprint in real time.
The platform integrates with open environmental APIs and IoT devices to provide live data on air quality, carbon output, waste management, and energy consumption.
It gamifies sustainability by rewarding eco-friendly actions and sharing community progress.
</proposed_solution>
<system_architecture>
Stack: React.js (Frontend) → Node.js/Express.js (Backend) → MongoDB Atlas (Database)
APIs: OpenWeatherMap, Carbon Interface API, and SmartCity Data APIs.
Hosting: Vercel (Frontend) & Render (Backend).
</system_architecture>
<key_features>
Authentication: JWT-based user login and role-based dashboards (citizens, NGOs, city admins).
Live Data: Real-time air quality, carbon usage, and waste tracking.
Gamification: Earn badges and points for eco-friendly actions.
Analytics: Charts and heatmaps to visualize sustainability metrics.
Community: Leaderboards and collaboration spaces for green initiatives.
</key_features>
<tech_stack>
Frontend: React.js, Tailwind CSS, Chart.js, React Router.
Backend: Node.js, Express.js, Axios.
Database: MongoDB Atlas.
Services: JWT, OpenWeatherMap API, Carbon Interface API.
Hosting: Vercel & Render.
</tech_stack>
<expected_impact>
- Empowers individuals to understand and reduce their carbon footprint.
- Promotes collaboration between citizens and local authorities for sustainability.
- Encourages eco-friendly lifestyles through gamification and public recognition.
</expected_impact>
<future_enhancements>
- Mobile app version with push notifications for environmental alerts.
- AI-driven personalized eco-tips based on user habits.
- Integration with IoT devices (smart meters, air sensors).
</future_enhancements>
<sys_created_by>adityarana</sys_created_by>
<sys_created_on>2025-10-31 12:30:00</sys_created_on>
</x_snc_hack4good_0_hack4good_proposal>
</record_update>
