<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<record_update>
  <record table="x_snc_hack4good_0_hack4good_proposal" action="insert" sys_id="9abc8def7ghi6jkl5mno4pqr3stu2vwx">
    <name>DisasterNet – AI-Powered Emergency Response & Coordination System</name>
    <short_description>ServiceNow-based platform for real-time disaster detection, response coordination, and citizen assistance.</short_description>
    <description><![CDATA[
Proposal Title: DisasterNet – AI-Powered Emergency Response & Coordination System

Summary:
DisasterNet is a ServiceNow-driven intelligent platform that leverages AI, IoT, and geospatial data to detect disasters, coordinate response teams, and assist affected citizens through automated workflows and communication channels.

Problem:
During natural disasters or crises, response time is critical. Current systems are fragmented, manual, and lack real-time coordination between emergency services, NGOs, and government agencies.

Solution:
DisasterNet provides a unified ServiceNow platform that automates response workflows, integrates live data streams, and enables instant collaboration between multiple agencies and responders.

Key Features:
1. AI-Driven Disaster Detection – Uses weather APIs, seismic data, and IoT sensors.
2. Real-Time Incident Dashboard – Displays heatmaps, severity levels, and updates.
3. Automated Task Routing – Assigns incidents to nearest available responders.
4. Citizen Assistance Portal – Allows citizens to request help via chatbot, SMS, or web form.
5. Resource & Logistics Tracker – Tracks available vehicles, supplies, and medical aid.
6. Situation Reports & Analytics – Generates live insights for decision-makers.

Target Users:
- Government disaster management departments
- NGOs and rescue organizations
- Hospitals and emergency response teams
- Citizens in affected areas

Integrations:
- Google Maps API / Esri ArcGIS
- Weather & Seismic APIs
- Twilio / WhatsApp
- Microsoft Teams / Slack
- ServiceNow Flow Designer & IntegrationHub

Impact:
- Speeds up emergency response times
- Reduces loss of life through real-time coordination
- Improves inter-agency collaboration
- Enables citizens to reach help faster through automation

Tech Stack:
- ServiceNow App Engine
- IntegrationHub for API connectivity
- Flow Designer for automation
- Virtual Agent for citizen communication
- Predictive Intelligence for risk scoring

Estimated Effort (MVP):
- 8–10 weeks for detection, routing, and citizen portal
- +3 weeks for AI-based analytics and maps integration

Author:
Hacktoberfest Contributor
Contact: placeholder@example.com

License:
MIT
]]></description>
    <author>Hacktoberfest Contributor</author>
    <category>Disaster Response & Crisis Management</category>
    <impact_statement>Accelerate disaster response through AI, automation, and cross-agency collaboration to protect communities in real time.</impact_statement>
    <features>AI Detection;Incident Dashboard;Automated Routing;Citizen Portal;Resource Tracker;Analytics Reports</features>
    <target_users>Governments, NGOs, hospitals, citizens</target_users>
    <integrations>Google Maps;Weather APIs;Twilio;Teams;Slack;ServiceNow AI</integrations>
    <estimated_effort>MVP: 8–10 weeks</estimated_effort>
    <license>MIT</license>
    <sys_created_on>2025-10-31 00:00:00</sys_created_on>
  </record>
</record_update>
