<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<record_update>
  <record table="x_snc_hack4good_0_hack4good_proposal" action="insert" sys_id="1234abcd5678efgh9012ijkl3456mnop">
    <name>EduFlow – AI-Powered Learning Support & Accessibility Platform</name>
    <short_description>Personalized AI assistant for learners and educators to enhance accessibility, engagement, and academic performance.</short_description>
    <description><![CDATA[
Proposal Title: EduFlow – AI-Powered Learning Support & Accessibility Platform

Summary:
EduFlow is a ServiceNow-based intelligent education assistant that supports students and teachers by automating routine academic workflows, enhancing accessibility for differently-abled learners, and providing personalized learning insights through AI.

Problem:
Educational institutions struggle with diverse learning needs, administrative overload, and lack of real-time academic support. Students often face barriers due to disabilities, stress, or limited guidance resources.

Solution:
EduFlow centralizes academic support with an AI-driven, inclusive learning assistant built on ServiceNow. It helps students learn efficiently, automates educator workflows, and fosters equal learning opportunities.

Key Features:
1. AI Learning Assistant – Personalized study recommendations and reminders.
2. Accessibility Tools – Speech-to-text, text-to-speech, and dyslexia-friendly modes.
3. Academic Workflow Automation – Auto attendance, assignment tracking, and grading alerts.
4. Student Wellness Monitoring – Early alerts for academic stress or disengagement.
5. Educator Dashboard – Insights into student progress and engagement trends.
6. Multilingual Support – Localized experience using ServiceNow AI Search.

Target Users:
- Universities and Colleges
- Online Learning Platforms
- K–12 Institutions
- Educators and Academic Advisors

Integrations:
- Microsoft Teams / Google Classroom
- Zoom / Slack
- ServiceNow Virtual Agent
- External EdTech APIs (Coursera, Khan Academy)

Impact:
- Promotes inclusive learning for all students
- Reduces educator workload through automation
- Enhances student engagement and retention
- Supports mental and academic wellness simultaneously

Tech Stack:
- ServiceNow App Engine
- Virtual Agent + AI Search
- Flow Designer
- IntegrationHub
- Predictive Intelligence

Estimated Effort (MVP):
- 6–9 weeks for core AI assistant, dashboards, and accessibility module
- +3 weeks for integrations and multilingual support

Author:
Hacktoberfest Contributor
Contact: placeholder@example.com

License:
MIT
]]></description>
    <author>Hacktoberfest Contributor</author>
    <category>Education & Accessibility</category>
    <impact_statement>Enable inclusive, intelligent, and automated learning support to transform the way students and educators connect through technology.</impact_statement>
    <features>AI Assistant;Accessibility Tools;Workflow Automation;Wellness Monitoring;Educator Dashboard;Multilingual Support</features>
    <target_users>Students, educators, institutions, edtech platforms</target_users>
    <integrations>Teams;Google Classroom;Slack;Zoom;Coursera;Khan Academy</integrations>
    <estimated_effort>MVP: 6–9 weeks</estimated_effort>
    <license>MIT</license>
    <sys_created_on>2025-10-31 00:00:00</sys_created_on>
  </record>
</record_update>
