<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<record_update>
<x_snc_hack4good_0_hack4good_proposal action="INSERT_OR_UPDATE">
<project_name>MindCare – AI Mental Wellness Assistant</project_name>
<focus_area>healthtech</focus_area>
<problem_statement>
Mental health awareness has grown, but many people still struggle with stress, burnout, and emotional well-being. 
Traditional therapy is often expensive, inaccessible, or stigmatized. 
There is a pressing need for a digital platform that provides accessible, affordable, and AI-driven mental wellness support.
</problem_statement>
<proposed_solution>
MindCare is an AI-powered mental wellness assistant that offers guided breathing exercises, emotion-based journaling, 
and mood analysis using natural language processing. It provides personalized wellness insights, motivation prompts, 
and emergency helpline suggestions based on detected emotional patterns.
</proposed_solution>
<system_architecture>
Stack: React.js (Frontend) → Node.js/Express.js (Backend) → MongoDB Atlas (Database)
Services: OpenAI API for sentiment analysis, JWT for secure authentication.
Hosting: Vercel (Frontend) & Render (Backend)
</system_architecture>
<key_features>
- AI-based emotion detection and personalized feedback
- Secure user journaling with daily mood tracking
- Breathing and mindfulness exercises with progress stats
- Interactive analytics dashboard showing mood trends
- Emergency contact suggestions based on mood severity
</key_features>
<tech_stack>
Frontend: React.js, Tailwind CSS, Axios
Backend: Node.js, Express.js
Database: MongoDB Atlas
APIs/Services: OpenAI API, JWT, Chart.js
</tech_stack>
<expected_impact>
- Improves emotional awareness and daily mental wellness
- Reduces stigma by offering private, AI-driven support
- Promotes mental resilience and stress management
</expected_impact>
<future_enhancements>
- Voice-based journal entries
- Integration with wearable devices for real-time stress tracking
- Personalized therapy recommendations via AI models
</future_enhancements>
<sys_created_by>adityarana</sys_created_by>
<sys_created_on>2025-10-31 13:00:00</sys_created_on>
</x_snc_hack4good_0_hack4good_proposal>
</record_update>
