<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<record_update>
  <record table="x_snc_hack4good_0_hack4good_proposal" action="insert" sys_id="fedcba0987654321fedcba0987654321">
    <name>EcoPulse – AI-Powered Sustainability & Carbon Footprint Tracker</name>
    <short_description>ServiceNow solution to measure, analyze, and reduce organizational carbon footprint using AI-driven insights.</short_description>
    <description><![CDATA[
Proposal Title: EcoPulse – AI-Powered Sustainability & Carbon Footprint Tracker

Summary:
EcoPulse is a ServiceNow-powered sustainability management platform that helps organizations track, report, and reduce their carbon emissions through intelligent data aggregation, AI-driven recommendations, and real-time dashboards.

Problem:
Most companies lack visibility into their daily carbon footprint and sustainability progress. Manual tracking is inefficient and often inaccurate, making it hard to take meaningful climate action.

Solution:
EcoPulse automates data collection from multiple systems (HR, facilities, logistics, and IT), calculates carbon metrics, and provides AI insights to reduce emissions.

Key Features:
1. Automated Data Collection – Integrates with ERP, IoT, and utility APIs.
2. Carbon Footprint Analytics – AI calculates energy, transport, and waste impact.
3. Smart Recommendations – Machine learning suggests ways to reduce emissions.
4. Sustainability Dashboard – Visual reports and compliance tracking.
5. Green Credits Tracker – Rewards teams for eco-friendly actions.
6. Automated Reporting – Generate ESG and sustainability reports instantly.

Target Users:
- Enterprises aiming for net-zero goals
- Government agencies
- Educational institutions
- NGOs focused on sustainability

Integrations:
- IoT sensors and smart meters
- SAP / Workday
- Google Cloud Carbon Footprint API
- ServiceNow Performance Analytics

Impact:
- Enables data-driven sustainability decisions
- Simplifies ESG reporting
- Encourages green behavior within organizations
- Accelerates progress toward carbon neutrality

Tech Stack:
- ServiceNow App Engine
- IntegrationHub (for external APIs)
- Flow Designer
- Predictive Intelligence & Performance Analytics

Estimated Effort (MVP):
- 6–8 weeks for data collection, dashboard, and AI insights
- +2 weeks for ESG reporting module

Author:
Hacktoberfest Contributor
Contact: placeholder@example.com

License:
MIT
]]></description>
    <author>Hacktoberfest Contributor</author>
    <category>Environment & Sustainability</category>
    <impact_statement>Empower organizations to take data-driven climate action with automated sustainability tracking and AI-powered carbon insights.</impact_statement>
    <features>Automated Data Collection;AI Insights;Carbon Analytics;Sustainability Dashboard;Smart Recommendations;ESG Reporting</features>
    <target_users>Enterprises, NGOs, governments, educational institutions</target_users>
    <integrations>IoT;SAP;Workday;Google Cloud APIs;ServiceNow Analytics</integrations>
    <estimated_effort>MVP: 6–8 weeks</estimated_effort>
    <license>MIT</license>
    <sys_created_on>2025-10-31 00:00:00</sys_created_on>
  </record>
</record_update>
