<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<record_update>
  <record table="x_snc_hack4good_0_hack4good_proposal" action="insert" sys_id="1234567890abcdef1234567890abcdef">
    <name>AI-Powered Crisis Relief Coordination Hub</name>
    <short_description>ServiceNow app to streamline disaster relief coordination using AI prioritization, real-time mapping, and automated workflows.</short_description>
    <description><![CDATA[
Proposal Title: AI-Powered Crisis Relief Coordination Hub

Summary:
A ServiceNow application that enables governments, NGOs, and volunteers to coordinate disaster relief operations efficiently. It uses AI for prioritization, real-time mapping, and automated task routing to ensure that help reaches affected areas faster and more effectively.

Problem:
During natural disasters, critical help requests are often lost, delayed, or duplicated. Agencies and NGOs lack a unified system to prioritize aid, assign resources, and track volunteer efforts — leading to inefficiency and delayed response times.

Solution:
The Crisis Relief Coordination Hub centralizes disaster response by:
1. Collecting requests via web form, chatbot, or WhatsApp.
2. Geo-tagging and classifying them by type (medical, shelter, food, etc.).
3. Using AI to prioritize based on urgency, density, and resource availability.
4. Automatically assigning tasks to the nearest available responder.
5. Displaying live dashboards for decision-makers to monitor progress.
6. Generating insights post-crisis for future preparedness.

Key Features:
- Real-Time Impact Dashboard — visualize affected areas and open tasks.
- AI Smart Prioritization — rank requests using severity and proximity.
- Omnichannel Intake — integrate web, SMS, and WhatsApp submissions.
- Dynamic Routing Engine — assign responders intelligently.
- Volunteer & Resource Registry — track availability and skills.
- Post-Relief Analytics — identify bottlenecks and optimize workflows.

Target Users:
- Disaster management agencies
- NGOs and relief organizations
- Volunteer networks
- Citizens in affected areas

Integrations:
- Google Maps / Mapbox APIs for mapping
- Twilio / WhatsApp for messaging
- Weather & Seismic APIs for predictive insights
- ServiceNow Flow Designer & IntegrationHub

Impact:
- Reduce response times by up to 60%
- Increase coordination and resource efficiency
- Provide data-driven insights for better preparedness
- Save more lives through faster, smarter action

Tech Stack:
- ServiceNow App Engine
- AI Search / Predictive Intelligence
- IntegrationHub for external data connectors

Estimated Effort (MVP):
- 6–10 weeks for intake form, routing engine, and dashboard
- +3–4 weeks for AI prioritization and analytics module

Author:
Hacktoberfest Contributor
Contact: placeholder@example.com

License:
MIT
]]></description>
    <author>Hacktoberfest Contributor</author>
    <category>Crisis Response</category>
    <impact_statement>Reduce response time and improve coordination during natural disasters through AI-driven prioritization and automated workflows.</impact_statement>
    <features>Real-Time Dashboard;AI Prioritization;Omnichannel Intake;Dynamic Routing;Volunteer Registry;Post-Relief Analytics</features>
    <target_users>Disaster management agencies, NGOs, volunteers, citizens</target_users>
    <integrations>Google Maps/Mapbox;Twilio/WhatsApp;Weather & Seismic APIs;ServiceNow IntegrationHub</integrations>
    <estimated_effort>MVP: 6-10 weeks</estimated_effort>
    <license>MIT</license>
    <sys_created_on>2025-10-31 00:00:00</sys_created_on>
  </record>
</record_update>
