<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><record_update table="x_snc_hack4good_0_hack4good_proposal">
    <x_snc_hack4good_0_hack4good_proposal action="INSERT_OR_UPDATE">
        <focus_area>education</focus_area>
        <notes/>
        <participation>yes</participation>
        <potential_impact><![CDATA[<p>A centralized and automated solution built on ServiceNow can streamline the entire process — from request intake to fulfillment and reporting.<br />By digitizing and automating this workflow:</p>
<ol><li>
<p>Students and coordinators can easily raise and track their support requests online.</p>
</li><li>
<p>NGOs can prioritize and assign requests efficiently using built-in workflows.</p>
</li><li>
<p>Donors or sponsors can get better transparency into how their contributions are utilized.</p>
</li><li>
<p>Data-driven insights can help NGOs identify demand patterns, improve allocation, and expand outreach.</p>
</li></ol>
<p>This solution ensures <strong>faster assistance, increased accountability, and greater educational reach</strong> for underprivileged students.</p>]]></potential_impact>
        <problem_statement>Many non-profit organizations working in the education sector receive numerous requests from students and communities seeking educational support — such as books, laptops, tuition aid, mentorship, or access to training programs.&#13;
Currently, most of these requests are handled manually through emails, phone calls, or spreadsheets, making it difficult to track the status, prioritize urgent cases, or ensure transparency in fund utilization.&#13;
This leads to delayed responses, unfulfilled needs, and limited visibility for both donors and NGO administrators.</problem_statement>
        <project_name>Education Support Request App</project_name>
        <solution_proposal><![CDATA[<h2><strong>How do you envision the ideal solution to this  problem?</strong></h2>
<p> </p>
<h3>Which ServiceNow products or capabilities would be used?</h3>
<p></p><p>The <strong>Education Support Request App</strong> will be a self-service portal where students or NGO representatives can log different types of education-related requests such as:</p>
<ol><li>
<p><strong>Book or stationery requests</strong></p>
</li><li>
<p><strong>Scholarship or sponsorship applications</strong></p>
</li><li>
<p><strong>Mentorship or tutoring support</strong></p>
</li><li>
<p><strong>Laptop or digital device assistance</strong></p>
</li></ol>
<p>Each request will be categorized, routed, and tracked through an automated ServiceNow workflow.<br />Admins can review, approve, or assign cases to relevant departments or volunteers.<br />Dashboards will show real-time data on open requests, response time, fulfilled cases, and geographical trends.<br />Donors could also be given limited access to view anonymized impact reports to foster transparency.</p>
<p> </p>
<hr style="border-top: 3px solid #bbb;" />
<h3>Are there any technical dependencies for the proposed solution?</h3>
<p></p><ol><li>
<p>Access to <strong>ServiceNow App Engine Studio</strong> and <strong>Flow Designer</strong> features.</p>
</li><li>
<p><strong>Email or Notification integration</strong> for communication with requesters and approvers.</p>
</li><li>
<p>(Optional) Integration with <strong>external donor databases</strong> or <strong>Google Sheets</strong> for NGOs who want to import/export data.</p>
</li><li>
<p>Basic NGO data model (list of students, schools, donors) to be configured for pilot testing.</p>
</li></ol>
<p> </p>
<hr style="border-top: 3px solid #bbb;" />
<h3>What challenges would you foresee in implementing this idea?</h3>
<p></p><ol><li>
<p><strong>Data privacy:</strong> Ensuring student information (like financial or academic details) is handled securely.</p>
</li><li>
<p><strong>Adoption &amp; accessibility:</strong> Some students may have limited internet access or digital literacy.</p>
</li><li>
<p><strong>Customization needs:</strong> NGOs may have different workflows or approval structures that require configuration flexibility.</p>
</li><li>
<p><strong>Integration complexity:</strong> If the NGO uses third-party donor systems, connecting them to ServiceNow may need API configuration.</p>
</li><li>
<p><strong>Licensing constraints:</strong> For smaller NGOs, access to full ServiceNow capabilities may depend on partnership or developer instance limits.</p>
</li></ol>]]></solution_proposal>
        <state>submitted</state>
        <sys_class_name>x_snc_hack4good_0_hack4good_proposal</sys_class_name>
        <sys_created_by>admin</sys_created_by>
        <sys_created_on>2025-10-31 17:23:06</sys_created_on>
        <sys_id>ff5ad4fb83b07210befc6830ceaad374</sys_id>
        <sys_mod_count>1</sys_mod_count>
        <sys_name>Education Support Request App</sys_name>
        <sys_package display_value="Hack4Good Idea Submission" source="x_snc_hack4good_0">95b5d2b7938832108543b2597bba109c</sys_package>
        <sys_policy/>
        <sys_scope display_value="Hack4Good Idea Submission">95b5d2b7938832108543b2597bba109c</sys_scope>
        <sys_update_name>x_snc_hack4good_0_hack4good_proposal_ff5ad4fb83b07210befc6830ceaad374</sys_update_name>
        <sys_updated_by>admin</sys_updated_by>
        <sys_updated_on>2025-10-31 17:23:09</sys_updated_on>
    </x_snc_hack4good_0_hack4good_proposal>
</record_update>
