<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><record_update table="x_snc_hack4good_0_hack4good_proposal">
    <x_snc_hack4good_0_hack4good_proposal action="INSERT_OR_UPDATE">
        <focus_area>education</focus_area>
        <notes/>
        <participation>no</participation>
        <potential_impact><![CDATA[<p>If ServiceNow can give a AI feature or Code intelligence feature to tackle mentioned problem, it will drastically reduce the coding hours and coding errors in workspace impelementation.</p>]]></potential_impact>
        <problem_statement>Developers are facing biggest challenge in convert UI Actions that are displayed both in Native UI and Workspace..&#13;
&#13;
Where they will write 2 separate client scripts one specific to Desktop view and one specific to Workspace view..&#13;
&#13;
Note: Workspace Client scripting is having a different format altogether and can be very challenging at times...&#13;
&#13;
This is very time consuming and complex to perform.&#13;
&#13;
&#13;
So if ServiceNow can come up with a AI feature or Code intelligence feature , that can analyze the Desktop view related Client script in a UI Action and generate a suggestion of Workspace Client script ...</problem_statement>
        <project_name>Now Assist or Code Intelligence feature that can help in suggesting or building Workspace UI Action Client Script from Desktop UI Action Client script</project_name>
        <solution_proposal><![CDATA[<h2><strong>How do you envision the ideal solution to this  problem?</strong></h2>
<p> </p>
<h3>Which ServiceNow products or capabilities would be used?</h3>
<p>No ServiceNow Products listed for this solution</p>
<p> </p>
<hr style="border-top: 3px solid #bbb;" />
<h3>Are there any technical dependencies for the proposed solution?</h3>
<p>No technical dependencies highlighted for this solution</p>
<p> </p>
<hr style="border-top: 3px solid #bbb;" />
<h3>What challenges would you foresee in implementing this idea?</h3>
<p>No particular challenges highlighted for this solution</p>]]></solution_proposal>
        <state>submitted</state>
        <sys_class_name>x_snc_hack4good_0_hack4good_proposal</sys_class_name>
        <sys_created_by>admin</sys_created_by>
        <sys_created_on>2025-10-27 22:23:59</sys_created_on>
        <sys_id>535738a2c3f83210727b190ed40131b4</sys_id>
        <sys_mod_count>1</sys_mod_count>
        <sys_name>Now Assist or Code Intelligence feature that can help in suggesting or building Workspace UI Action Client Script from Desktop UI Action Client script</sys_name>
        <sys_package display_value="Hack4Good Idea Submission" source="x_snc_hack4good_0">95b5d2b7938832108543b2597bba109c</sys_package>
        <sys_policy/>
        <sys_scope display_value="Hack4Good Idea Submission">95b5d2b7938832108543b2597bba109c</sys_scope>
        <sys_update_name>x_snc_hack4good_0_hack4good_proposal_535738a2c3f83210727b190ed40131b4</sys_update_name>
        <sys_updated_by>admin</sys_updated_by>
        <sys_updated_on>2025-10-27 22:24:00</sys_updated_on>
    </x_snc_hack4good_0_hack4good_proposal>
</record_update>
