<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><record_update table="x_snc_hack4good_0_hack4good_proposal">
    <x_snc_hack4good_0_hack4good_proposal action="INSERT_OR_UPDATE">
        <focus_area>disaster</focus_area>
        <notes/>
        <participation>yes</participation>
        <potential_impact><![CDATA[<p>A unified platform would enable seamless coordination of resources, volunteers, and donations, ensuring faster and more effective response times during disasters. The system would help avoid duplication of efforts and ensure critical supplies are allocated where needed most.</p>]]></potential_impact>
        <problem_statement>Disaster relief efforts often suffer from inefficient coordination between volunteers, donors, and local authorities, leading to delays and missed opportunities for helping those in need.</problem_statement>
        <project_name> Disaster relief Coordination System</project_name>
        <solution_proposal><![CDATA[<h2><strong>How do you envision the ideal solution to this  problem?</strong></h2>
<p> </p>
<h3>Which ServiceNow products or capabilities would be used?</h3>
<p></p><p>The system would include volunteer sign-ups, resource allocation (food, medicine, etc.), and real-time reporting of affected areas. Volunteers would be able to track their assigned tasks, while donors can track how their contributions are being used.</p>
<p> </p>
<hr style="border-top: 3px solid #bbb;" />
<h3>Are there any technical dependencies for the proposed solution?</h3>
<p></p><ul><li>ServiceNow Incident Management</li><li>Service Catalog</li><li>Event Management</li><li>Mobile App</li><li>Geolocation integration to track affected areas, mobile capabilities for volunteers, and real-time communication tools.</li></ul>
<p> </p>
<hr style="border-top: 3px solid #bbb;" />
<h3>What challenges would you foresee in implementing this idea?</h3>
<p></p><p>Real-time data accuracy and consistency could be difficult to achieve in a disaster setting, where infrastructure may be damaged. Ensuring the system works in low-connectivity environments is also a potential challenge.</p>]]></solution_proposal>
        <state>submitted</state>
        <sys_class_name>x_snc_hack4good_0_hack4good_proposal</sys_class_name>
        <sys_created_by>admin</sys_created_by>
        <sys_created_on>2025-10-22 09:59:37</sys_created_on>
        <sys_id>1c571c303b7432109f3ed10f23e45ae3</sys_id>
        <sys_mod_count>1</sys_mod_count>
        <sys_name> Disaster Relief Coordination System</sys_name>
        <sys_package display_value="Hack4Good Idea Submission" source="x_snc_hack4good_0">95b5d2b7938832108543b2597bba109c</sys_package>
        <sys_policy/>
        <sys_scope display_value="Hack4Good Idea Submission">95b5d2b7938832108543b2597bba109c</sys_scope>
        <sys_update_name>x_snc_hack4good_0_hack4good_proposal_1c571c303b7432109f3ed10f23e45ae3</sys_update_name>
        <sys_updated_by>admin</sys_updated_by>
        <sys_updated_on>2025-10-22 09:59:41</sys_updated_on>
    </x_snc_hack4good_0_hack4good_proposal>
</record_update>
