<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><record_update table="x_snc_hack4good_0_hack4good_proposal">
    <x_snc_hack4good_0_hack4good_proposal action="INSERT_OR_UPDATE">
        <focus_area>education</focus_area>
        <notes/>
        <participation>yes</participation>
        <potential_impact><![CDATA[<p>A digital classroom management tool would help youth education nonprofits streamline their operations, reduce administrative overhead, and improve student engagement, leading to better learning outcomes.</p>]]></potential_impact>
        <problem_statement>Many youth education nonprofits face challenges with managing remote learning, attendance tracking, assignments, and communication between teachers, students, and parents. A unified system for managing these interactions is often lacking.</problem_statement>
        <project_name>Digital Classroom Management System</project_name>
        <solution_proposal><![CDATA[<h2><strong>How do you envision the ideal solution to this  problem?</strong></h2>
<p> </p>
<h3>Which ServiceNow products or capabilities would be used?</h3>
<p></p><p>The system would allow teachers to create courses, assign homework, and track attendance. Students can submit assignments, view grades, and communicate with teachers. Parents can access performance reports and receive notifications of important events. Integration with ServiceNow’s Service Catalog can allow for additional learning resources like tutoring or materials.</p>
<p> </p>
<hr style="border-top: 3px solid #bbb;" />
<h3>Are there any technical dependencies for the proposed solution?</h3>
<p></p><ul><li>Integrations with third-party learning tools (Google Classroom, Microsoft Teams) and secure messaging platforms.</li><li>Service Catalog</li><li>Knowledge Management</li><li>Reporting &amp; Dashboard</li><li>Mobile App</li></ul>
<p> </p>
<hr style="border-top: 3px solid #bbb;" />
<h3>What challenges would you foresee in implementing this idea?</h3>
<p></p><p>Ensuring user adoption, especially for parents and students who may not be tech-savvy. Ensuring data privacy and security for children’s information would also be a challenge.</p>]]></solution_proposal>
        <state>submitted</state>
        <sys_class_name>x_snc_hack4good_0_hack4good_proposal</sys_class_name>
        <sys_created_by>admin</sys_created_by>
        <sys_created_on>2025-10-22 10:07:29</sys_created_on>
        <sys_id>6140a03c3b7432109f3ed10f23e45a6e</sys_id>
        <sys_mod_count>1</sys_mod_count>
        <sys_name>Digital Classroom Management System</sys_name>
        <sys_package display_value="Hack4Good Idea Submission" source="x_snc_hack4good_0">95b5d2b7938832108543b2597bba109c</sys_package>
        <sys_policy/>
        <sys_scope display_value="Hack4Good Idea Submission">95b5d2b7938832108543b2597bba109c</sys_scope>
        <sys_update_name>x_snc_hack4good_0_hack4good_proposal_6140a03c3b7432109f3ed10f23e45a6e</sys_update_name>
        <sys_updated_by>admin</sys_updated_by>
        <sys_updated_on>2025-10-22 10:07:31</sys_updated_on>
    </x_snc_hack4good_0_hack4good_proposal>
</record_update>
