<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><record_update table="x_snc_hack4good_0_hack4good_proposal">
    <x_snc_hack4good_0_hack4good_proposal action="INSERT_OR_UPDATE">
        <focus_area>disaster</focus_area>
        <notes/>
        <participation>yes</participation>
        <potential_impact><![CDATA[<p style="margin-top: 12pt; margin-bottom: 12pt;"><strong><span style="font-size: 11pt; font-family: Arial, sans-serif;">Continuity of Care:</span></strong><span style="font-size: 11pt; font-family: Arial, sans-serif;"> Ensure 100% of critical information (medical, educational, legal, therapeutic) transfers seamlessly across placements</span></p>
<p style="margin-top: 12pt; margin-bottom: 12pt;"><strong><span style="font-size: 11pt; font-family: Arial, sans-serif;">Educational Outcomes:</span></strong><span style="font-size: 11pt; font-family: Arial, sans-serif;"> 50% increase in high school graduation rates through consistent academic tracking and support</span></p>
<p style="margin-top: 12pt; margin-bottom: 12pt;"><strong><span style="font-size: 11pt; font-family: Arial, sans-serif;">Healthcare Improvement:</span></strong><span style="font-size: 11pt; font-family: Arial, sans-serif;"> 80% reduction in missed medical appointments and medication errors through coordinated care</span></p>
<p style="margin-top: 12pt; margin-bottom: 12pt;"><strong><span style="font-size: 11pt; font-family: Arial, sans-serif;">Placement Stability:</span></strong><span style="font-size: 11pt; font-family: Arial, sans-serif;"> 40% reduction in placement disruptions through better matching and early intervention</span></p>
<p style="margin-top: 12pt; margin-bottom: 12pt;"><strong><span style="font-size: 11pt; font-family: Arial, sans-serif;">Caseworker Efficiency:</span></strong><span style="font-size: 11pt; font-family: Arial, sans-serif;"> Save 15-20 hours per week per caseworker through automated documentation and coordination</span></p>
<p style="margin-top: 12pt; margin-bottom: 12pt;"><strong><span style="font-size: 11pt; font-family: Arial, sans-serif;">Aging Out Success:</span></strong><span style="font-size: 11pt; font-family: Arial, sans-serif;"> 60% improvement in outcomes for youth aging out (housing, employment, education) through transition planning</span></p>
<p style="margin-top: 12pt; margin-bottom: 12pt;"><strong><span style="font-size: 11pt; font-family: Arial, sans-serif;">Cost Savings:</span></strong><span style="font-size: 11pt; font-family: Arial, sans-serif;"> $8,000-12,000 per child annually through reduced emergency interventions and placement failures</span></p>
<p style="margin-top: 12pt; margin-bottom: 12pt;"><strong><span style="font-size: 11pt; font-family: Arial, sans-serif;">Scale:</span></strong><span style="font-size: 11pt; font-family: Arial, sans-serif;"> Support 400,000&#43; foster children nationwide with coordinated, continuous care</span></p>]]></potential_impact>
        <problem_statement>Foster children experience some of the worst outcomes in society due to fragmented care coordination. A single child may interact with 20+ different professionals (caseworkers, foster parents, therapists, doctors, teachers, lawyers, court officials) across multiple placements, often experiencing 3-7 moves before age 18. Each transition disrupts education, healthcare, therapy, and relationships. Critical information gets lost between placements—medical records, educational IEPs, therapy progress, medication lists, trauma history, and family connections. Caseworkers carry 30+ cases each and struggle to maintain continuity. This fragmentation leads to educational delays (60% of foster youth don't graduate high school), health risks (missed vaccinations, medication errors), mental health crises, and poor long-term outcomes (25% experience homelessness within 4 years of aging out).</problem_statement>
        <project_name>FosterCare360 - Foster Child Care Coordination</project_name>
        <solution_proposal><![CDATA[<h2><strong>How do you envision the ideal solution to this  problem?</strong></h2>
<p> </p>
<h3>Which ServiceNow products or capabilities would be used?</h3>
<p></p><p>A comprehensive ServiceNow-based platform creating a &#34;digital care passport&#34; for each foster child that follows them throughout their journey. The system maintains a complete, longitudinal record including medical history, educational records, therapy notes, legal documents, family connections, trauma-informed care plans, and developmental milestones. When a child moves placements, new caregivers instantly access essential information while respecting privacy controls.</p>
<p>Key features include: automated care team coordination across all professionals involved with the child; intelligent matching algorithms pairing children with appropriate foster homes based on needs, location, and family capabilities; workflow automation for court hearings, medical appointments, school enrollments, and therapy sessions; secure document vault for birth certificates, Social Security cards, immunization records, and court orders; mobile app for foster parents to log daily observations, administer medications, and communicate with caseworkers; therapy and behavioral tracking tools; educational progress monitoring with IEP management; family connection tracking to maintain sibling and biological family relationships; transition planning modules for aging-out youth (18-21); and analytics dashboards for agencies to identify at-risk children and allocate resources effectively.</p>
<p>The platform includes privacy controls ensuring only authorized individuals access sensitive information, emergency alert systems for crisis situations, and integration with schools, healthcare providers, courts, and social service agencies.</p>
<h3> <strong>Which ServiceNow products or capabilities would be used?</strong></h3>
<p> </p>
<ol><li style="list-style-type: none;">
<ol><li>
<p><strong>Customer Service Management (CSM)</strong> - Multi-agency case management and care coordination across all professionals</p>
</li><li>
<p><strong>Now Platform App Engine</strong> - Custom foster care workflows, placement matching, and care plan management</p>
</li><li>
<p><strong>Integration Hub</strong> - Connect schools, healthcare providers, courts, child welfare systems, background check services</p>
</li><li>
<p><strong>Mobile Studio</strong> - Foster parent mobile app for daily logging, medication tracking, and communication</p>
</li><li>
<p><strong>Document Management</strong> - Secure lifetime record storage (medical, educational, legal documents)</p>
</li><li>
<p><strong>Employee Center</strong> - Caseworker collaboration hub with shared case visibility</p>
</li><li>
<p><strong>Performance Analytics</strong> - Track child outcomes, placement stability, service gaps, and caseload management</p>
</li><li>
<p><strong>Service Portal</strong> - Self-service access for foster parents, biological parents (when appropriate), and older youth</p>
</li><li>
<p><strong>Virtual Agent</strong> - AI-powered guidance for foster parents on common questions and procedures</p>
</li><li>
<p><strong>Flow Designer</strong> - Automated workflows for placement transitions, appointment scheduling, court date reminders</p>
</li><li>
<p><strong>Now Assist</strong> - AI recommendations for placement matching, risk assessment, and resource allocation</p>
</li><li>
<p><strong>Field Service Management</strong> - Schedule and dispatch home visits, inspections, and family assessments</p>
</li><li><strong>Public Sector Digital Services (PSDS):</strong> For citizen-facing requests and social case tracking.</li></ol>
</li></ol>
<p> </p>
<hr style="border-top: 3px solid #bbb;" />
<h3>Are there any technical dependencies for the proposed solution?</h3>
<p></p><p> </p>
<ol><li style="list-style-type: none;">
<ol><li>
<p>School district student information systems (PowerSchool, Infinite Campus)</p>
</li><li>State child welfare systems (SACWIS, CCWIS)</li><li>
<p>Electronic Health Records (EHR) systems (Epic, Cerner)</p>
</li><li>
<p>Court case management systems (Odyssey, Tyler Technologies)</p>
</li><li>
<p>Background check and licensing databases (FBI, state clearances)</p>
</li><li>
<p>Healthcare provider directories and scheduling systems</p>
</li><li>
<p>Therapy and behavioral health platforms</p>
</li><li>
<p>Educational assessment and IEP management systems</p>
</li><li>
<p>Birth certificate and vital records databases</p>
</li><li>
<p>Immunization registries (state health departments)</p>
</li><li>
<p>Medication management systems</p>
</li><li>
<p>Foster parent licensing and training platforms</p>
</li><li>
<p>Youth development and independent living programs</p>
</li><li>
<p>SMS/communication gateways (Twilio)</p>
</li><li>
<p>Document verification and e-signature services (DocuSign)</p>
</li><li>
<p>Translation services for non-English speaking families</p>
</li><li>
<p>Mental health crisis hotlines and emergency services</p>
</li></ol>
</li></ol>
<p> </p>
<hr style="border-top: 3px solid #bbb;" />
<h3>What challenges would you foresee in implementing this idea?</h3>
<p></p><p style="margin-top: 12pt; margin-bottom: 12pt;"><strong><span style="font-size: 11pt; font-family: Arial, sans-serif;">Data Privacy &amp; Security:</span></strong><span style="font-size: 11pt; font-family: Arial, sans-serif;"> Handling highly sensitive child welfare information, HIPAA compliance, FERPA compliance, court-sealed records, and varying state privacy laws requiring role-based access controls and audit trails</span></p>
<p style="margin-top: 12pt; margin-bottom: 12pt;"><strong><span style="font-size: 11pt; font-family: Arial, sans-serif;">Multi-Jurisdictional Complexity:</span></strong><span style="font-size: 11pt; font-family: Arial, sans-serif;"> Foster care is state-administered with 50&#43; different systems, policies, regulations, and data standards; interstate placements add additional complexity</span></p>
<p style="margin-top: 12pt; margin-bottom: 12pt;"><strong><span style="font-size: 11pt; font-family: Arial, sans-serif;">Stakeholder Coordination:</span></strong><span style="font-size: 11pt; font-family: Arial, sans-serif;"> Aligning competing priorities and workflows across child welfare agencies, courts, schools, healthcare providers, foster care agencies, biological parents, and advocates</span></p>
<p style="margin-top: 12pt; margin-bottom: 12pt;"><strong><span style="font-size: 11pt; font-family: Arial, sans-serif;">Legacy System Integration:</span></strong><span style="font-size: 11pt; font-family: Arial, sans-serif;"> Most state child welfare systems run on outdated technology (30&#43; year old COBOL systems) that are difficult to integrate</span></p>
<p style="margin-top: 12pt; margin-bottom: 12pt;"><strong><span style="font-size: 11pt; font-family: Arial, sans-serif;">Change Management:</span></strong><span style="font-size: 11pt; font-family: Arial, sans-serif;"> Caseworkers overwhelmed with high caseloads may resist new technology; extensive training and support needed</span></p>
<p style="margin-top: 12pt; margin-bottom: 12pt;"><strong><span style="font-size: 11pt; font-family: Arial, sans-serif;">Trauma-Informed Design:</span></strong><span style="font-size: 11pt; font-family: Arial, sans-serif;"> Platform must respect trauma histories and avoid re-traumatizing children and families through insensitive data collection or sharing</span></p>
<p style="margin-top: 12pt; margin-bottom: 12pt;"><strong><span style="font-size: 11pt; font-family: Arial, sans-serif;">Funding &amp; Sustainability:</span></strong><span style="font-size: 11pt; font-family: Arial, sans-serif;"> Child welfare agencies are chronically underfunded; securing sustained funding across multiple state and federal sources</span></p>
<p style="margin-top: 12pt; margin-bottom: 12pt;"><strong><span style="font-size: 11pt; font-family: Arial, sans-serif;">Digital Divide:</span></strong><span style="font-size: 11pt; font-family: Arial, sans-serif;"> Foster families in rural areas may lack reliable internet; older youth may lack devices or digital literacy</span></p>
<p style="margin-top: 12pt; margin-bottom: 12pt;"><strong><span style="font-size: 11pt; font-family: Arial, sans-serif;">Information Overload:</span></strong><span style="font-size: 11pt; font-family: Arial, sans-serif;"> Risk of overwhelming caregivers with too much information; need smart filtering and prioritization</span></p>
<p style="margin-top: 12pt; margin-bottom: 12pt;"><strong><span style="font-size: 11pt; font-family: Arial, sans-serif;">Cultural Sensitivity:</span></strong><span style="font-size: 11pt; font-family: Arial, sans-serif;"> Foster care disproportionately affects minority communities; platform must be culturally responsive and address systemic biases</span></p>
<p style="margin-top: 12pt; margin-bottom: 12pt;"><strong><span style="font-size: 11pt; font-family: Arial, sans-serif;">Youth Voice:</span></strong><span style="font-size: 11pt; font-family: Arial, sans-serif;"> Ensuring older youth have appropriate access and control over their own information while respecting safety requirements</span></p>
<p style="margin-top: 12pt; margin-bottom: 12pt;"><strong><span style="font-size: 11pt; font-family: Arial, sans-serif;">Legal Compliance:</span></strong><span style="font-size: 11pt; font-family: Arial, sans-serif;"> Navigating complex state and federal regulations (Title IV-E, CAPTA, ICWA) and court order requirements</span></p>]]></solution_proposal>
        <state>submitted</state>
        <sys_class_name>x_snc_hack4good_0_hack4good_proposal</sys_class_name>
        <sys_created_by>admin</sys_created_by>
        <sys_created_on>2025-10-31 17:55:35</sys_created_on>
        <sys_id>50ced4f3933c7ad09edefa497bba10ae</sys_id>
        <sys_mod_count>1</sys_mod_count>
        <sys_name>FosterCare360 - Foster Child Care Coordination</sys_name>
        <sys_package display_value="Hack4Good Idea Submission" source="x_snc_hack4good_0">95b5d2b7938832108543b2597bba109c</sys_package>
        <sys_policy/>
        <sys_scope display_value="Hack4Good Idea Submission">95b5d2b7938832108543b2597bba109c</sys_scope>
        <sys_update_name>x_snc_hack4good_0_hack4good_proposal_50ced4f3933c7ad09edefa497bba10ae</sys_update_name>
        <sys_updated_by>admin</sys_updated_by>
        <sys_updated_on>2025-10-31 17:55:37</sys_updated_on>
    </x_snc_hack4good_0_hack4good_proposal>
</record_update>
