<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><record_update table="x_snc_hack4good_0_hack4good_proposal">
    <x_snc_hack4good_0_hack4good_proposal action="INSERT_OR_UPDATE">
        <focus_area>other</focus_area>
        <notes/>
        <participation>yes</participation>
        <potential_impact><![CDATA[<p>A centralized, real-time Shelter Availability Finder would:</p>
<ol><li>
<p>Help citizens quickly locate the nearest available shelter with capacity and basic amenities.</p>
</li><li>
<p>Assist government agencies and NGOs in tracking shelter occupancy, resources, and needs dynamically.</p>
</li><li>
<p>Enable faster decision-making and better allocation of emergency resources.</p>
</li><li>
<p>Improve overall disaster response efficiency, reducing loss of life and hardship during crises</p>
</li></ol>]]></potential_impact>
        <problem_statement>During emergencies such as floods, earthquakes, or other natural disasters, finding nearby safe shelters becomes extremely difficult for affected people and for relief organizations managing resources. Current systems often rely on manual coordination or outdated data, leading to overcrowding in some shelters while others remain underutilized. Additionally, relief workers struggle to track real-time shelter capacities and essential supplies like food, blankets, and medical support.</problem_statement>
        <project_name>Shelter Availability Finder</project_name>
        <solution_proposal><![CDATA[<h2><strong>How do you envision the ideal solution to this  problem?</strong></h2>
<p> </p>
<h3>Which ServiceNow products or capabilities would be used?</h3>
<p></p><p>The ideal solution would be a <strong>ServiceNow-based application</strong> that integrates with location services, shelter management records, and emergency response systems. Key features would include:</p>
<ol><li>
<p><strong>Real-time Shelter Dashboard:</strong> Displays all active shelters, their locations, capacity, and available facilities.</p>
</li><li>
<p><strong>Citizen Portal:</strong> Allows affected individuals to search for the nearest available shelter using GPS or pin code.</p>
</li><li>
<p><strong>Shelter Manager Workspace:</strong> Enables shelter coordinators to update capacity, mark resources, and report urgent needs.</p>
</li><li>
<p><strong>Automated Notifications:</strong> Sends alerts to citizens about nearby shelters or changes in availability.</p>
</li><li>
<p><strong>Reporting &amp; Analytics:</strong> Helps authorities analyze occupancy trends and optimize future disaster preparedness.</p>
</li></ol>
<p> </p>
<hr style="border-top: 3px solid #bbb;" />
<h3>Are there any technical dependencies for the proposed solution?</h3>
<p></p><ol><li>
<p>Integration with <strong>geolocation APIs</strong> (e.g., Google Maps or OpenStreetMap) for real-time mapping.</p>
</li><li>
<p>Data feed from <strong>local authorities or NGOs</strong> maintaining shelter information.</p>
</li><li>
<p>Internet connectivity for field users or mobile apps to update and retrieve data.</p>
</li><li>
<p>Optional: Integration with <strong>SMS gateways or WhatsApp APIs</strong> for citizens who lack smartphone access.</p>
</li></ol>
<p> </p>
<hr style="border-top: 3px solid #bbb;" />
<h3>What challenges would you foresee in implementing this idea?</h3>
<p></p><ol><li>
<p><strong>Data Accuracy:</strong> Keeping shelter availability and resource data up to date in real time.</p>
</li><li>
<p><strong>Connectivity Issues:</strong> During disasters, network coverage may be poor, affecting system access.</p>
</li><li>
<p><strong>User Adoption:</strong> Ensuring local authorities, volunteers, and citizens are trained and motivated to use the system.</p>
</li><li>
<p><strong>Integration Complexity:</strong> Aligning multiple data sources from various NGOs or government systems.</p>
</li><li>
<p><strong>Privacy &amp; Security:</strong> Protecting user and shelter data from misuse or unauthorized access.</p>
</li></ol>]]></solution_proposal>
        <state>submitted</state>
        <sys_class_name>x_snc_hack4good_0_hack4good_proposal</sys_class_name>
        <sys_created_by>admin</sys_created_by>
        <sys_created_on>2025-10-31 18:07:21</sys_created_on>
        <sys_id>75c4e4fb83f07210befc6830ceaad33c</sys_id>
        <sys_mod_count>1</sys_mod_count>
        <sys_name>Shelter Availability Finder</sys_name>
        <sys_package display_value="Hack4Good Idea Submission" source="x_snc_hack4good_0">95b5d2b7938832108543b2597bba109c</sys_package>
        <sys_policy/>
        <sys_scope display_value="Hack4Good Idea Submission">95b5d2b7938832108543b2597bba109c</sys_scope>
        <sys_update_name>x_snc_hack4good_0_hack4good_proposal_75c4e4fb83f07210befc6830ceaad33c</sys_update_name>
        <sys_updated_by>admin</sys_updated_by>
        <sys_updated_on>2025-10-31 18:07:23</sys_updated_on>
    </x_snc_hack4good_0_hack4good_proposal>
</record_update>
