<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><record_update table="x_snc_hack4good_0_hack4good_proposal">
    <x_snc_hack4good_0_hack4good_proposal action="INSERT_OR_UPDATE">
        <focus_area>cure</focus_area>
        <notes/>
        <participation>yes</participation>
        <potential_impact><![CDATA[<p>This platform would simplify the process for companies to match donations, track volunteer hours, and report on the impact of their CSR efforts, fostering more meaningful corporate engagement and social responsibility.</p>]]></potential_impact>
        <problem_statement>Many companies struggle to manage corporate social responsibility (CSR) programs that include both volunteerism and monetary donations, and tracking the impact of those efforts is often disjointed.</problem_statement>
        <project_name>Corporate Giving &amp; Volunteering Platform</project_name>
        <solution_proposal><![CDATA[<h2><strong>How do you envision the ideal solution to this  problem?</strong></h2>
<p> </p>
<h3>Which ServiceNow products or capabilities would be used?</h3>
<p></p><p>The platform would allow companies to create campaigns for donations and volunteer opportunities. Employees could track their hours and make donation pledges, with results and impact reports generated on the backend.</p>
<p> </p>
<hr style="border-top: 3px solid #bbb;" />
<h3>Are there any technical dependencies for the proposed solution?</h3>
<p></p><ul><li>Integrating with external payroll and donation systems, as well as providing tools for employees to easily log volunteer hours and donations.</li><li>CSR Integration in ServiceNow HR Service Delivery</li><li>Reporting &amp; Dashboard</li><li>CSR Integration with HRSD</li></ul>
<p> </p>
<hr style="border-top: 3px solid #bbb;" />
<h3>What challenges would you foresee in implementing this idea?</h3>
<p></p><p>Balancing user engagement with a seamless experience, especially ensuring that the platform is easy to use for all employees and provides meaningful insights for employers.</p>]]></solution_proposal>
        <state>submitted</state>
        <sys_class_name>x_snc_hack4good_0_hack4good_proposal</sys_class_name>
        <sys_created_by>admin</sys_created_by>
        <sys_created_on>2025-10-22 10:09:15</sys_created_on>
        <sys_id>efe0207c3b7432109f3ed10f23e45a38</sys_id>
        <sys_mod_count>1</sys_mod_count>
        <sys_name>Corporate Giving &amp; Volunteering Platform</sys_name>
        <sys_package display_value="Hack4Good Idea Submission" source="x_snc_hack4good_0">95b5d2b7938832108543b2597bba109c</sys_package>
        <sys_policy/>
        <sys_scope display_value="Hack4Good Idea Submission">95b5d2b7938832108543b2597bba109c</sys_scope>
        <sys_update_name>x_snc_hack4good_0_hack4good_proposal_efe0207c3b7432109f3ed10f23e45a38</sys_update_name>
        <sys_updated_by>admin</sys_updated_by>
        <sys_updated_on>2025-10-22 10:09:17</sys_updated_on>
    </x_snc_hack4good_0_hack4good_proposal>
</record_update>
