<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><record_update table="x_snc_hack4good_0_hack4good_proposal">
    <x_snc_hack4good_0_hack4good_proposal action="INSERT_OR_UPDATE">
        <focus_area>other</focus_area>
        <notes/>
        <participation>yes</participation>
        <potential_impact><![CDATA[<p>Implementing a centralized, automated solution would:</p>
<ol><li>
<p>Provide real-time visibility into carbon emissions, energy consumption, and resource utilization.</p>
</li><li>
<p>Help organizations track progress toward sustainability goals such as carbon neutrality or waste reduction.</p>
</li><li>
<p>Simplify regulatory reporting and compliance with frameworks like ESG, ISO 14001, or government sustainability standards.</p>
</li><li>
<p>Enable data-driven decision-making to optimize processes and reduce the environmental footprint.</p>
</li><li>
<p>Foster employee engagement by encouraging sustainable actions through dashboards and gamified initiatives.</p>
</li></ol>]]></potential_impact>
        <problem_statement>Many organizations struggle to accurately measure, track, and reduce their environmental impact due to scattered data sources, manual reporting, and lack of visibility into sustainability metrics.&#13;
Key challenges include:&#13;
&#13;
Limited transparency into carbon emissions and energy consumption across departments.&#13;
&#13;
Inconsistent methods for tracking waste, water usage, and renewable resource adoption.&#13;
&#13;
Difficulty in aligning sustainability goals with operational processes.&#13;
&#13;
Lack of a centralized system to report progress on sustainability initiatives or compliance with environmental regulations.</problem_statement>
        <project_name>Environment &amp; Sustainability</project_name>
        <solution_proposal><![CDATA[<h2><strong>How do you envision the ideal solution to this  problem?</strong></h2>
<p> </p>
<h3>Which ServiceNow products or capabilities would be used?</h3>
<p></p><p>The <strong>Sustainability &amp; Carbon Footprint Management Portal</strong> will serve as a unified dashboard within ServiceNow to:</p>
<ol><li>
<p>Collect and consolidate data from facilities, transportation, and procurement systems.</p>
</li><li>
<p>Calculate and visualize carbon emissions, water usage, and waste management trends using custom widgets and reports.</p>
</li><li>
<p>Generate automated sustainability reports for internal teams and external regulators.</p>
</li><li>
<p>Provide workflows for sustainability initiatives (e.g., “Green Projects”) to track actions, approvals, and outcomes.</p>
</li><li>
<p>Include an employee engagement module to encourage participation in eco-friendly practices and track personal contributions.</p>
</li><li>
<p>Use predictive analytics to recommend areas for resource optimization and emission reduction.</p>
</li></ol>
<p> </p>
<hr style="border-top: 3px solid #bbb;" />
<h3>Are there any technical dependencies for the proposed solution?</h3>
<p></p><ol><li>
<p>Integration with external energy management and IoT platforms for real-time data collection.</p>
</li><li>
<p>Access to organizational data on energy usage, transportation, and procurement.</p>
</li><li>
<p>Availability of APIs or data feeds from existing sustainability or ERP systems.</p>
</li><li>
<p>Configuration of ESG Management and Performance Analytics modules.</p>
</li></ol>
<p> </p>
<hr style="border-top: 3px solid #bbb;" />
<h3>What challenges would you foresee in implementing this idea?</h3>
<p></p><ol><li>
<p>Ensuring accurate and consistent data collection from diverse sources.</p>
</li><li>
<p>Integrating legacy systems that may not have open APIs or standardized data formats.</p>
</li><li>
<p>Managing organizational change and encouraging adoption of sustainability workflows.</p>
</li><li>
<p>Establishing baseline sustainability metrics before tracking improvements.</p>
</li><li>
<p>Potential licensing or cost implications for ESG and analytics modules.</p>
</li></ol>]]></solution_proposal>
        <state>submitted</state>
        <sys_class_name>x_snc_hack4good_0_hack4good_proposal</sys_class_name>
        <sys_created_by>admin</sys_created_by>
        <sys_created_on>2025-10-31 18:14:01</sys_created_on>
        <sys_id>4e06243383347210befc6830ceaad3f1</sys_id>
        <sys_mod_count>1</sys_mod_count>
        <sys_name>Environment &amp; Sustainability</sys_name>
        <sys_package display_value="Hack4Good Idea Submission" source="x_snc_hack4good_0">95b5d2b7938832108543b2597bba109c</sys_package>
        <sys_policy/>
        <sys_scope display_value="Hack4Good Idea Submission">95b5d2b7938832108543b2597bba109c</sys_scope>
        <sys_update_name>x_snc_hack4good_0_hack4good_proposal_4e06243383347210befc6830ceaad3f1</sys_update_name>
        <sys_updated_by>admin</sys_updated_by>
        <sys_updated_on>2025-10-31 18:14:03</sys_updated_on>
    </x_snc_hack4good_0_hack4good_proposal>
</record_update>
