<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><record_update table="x_snc_hack4good_0_hack4good_proposal">
    <x_snc_hack4good_0_hack4good_proposal action="INSERT_OR_UPDATE">
        <focus_area>education</focus_area>
        <notes/>
        <participation>yes</participation>
        <potential_impact><![CDATA[<p>Waste Diversion (Measurable): Tracks the volume (in pounds or kilograms) of organic waste diverted from landfills per month, providing concrete data for municipal sustainability goals.</p>
<p>Increased Participation (20%): Simplifies the process of finding and using community composting resources, encouraging broader participation.</p>
<p>Soil Enrichment: The resulting compost supports local community gardens and urban farming initiatives, creating a positive feedback loop for local food systems.</p>]]></potential_impact>
        <problem_statement>Residential food waste and yard waste constitute a significant portion of municipal solid waste, contributing to methane emissions in landfills. While composting is a sustainable alternative, many residents face barriers:&#13;
&#13;
Lack of Infrastructure: They don't have the space, knowledge, or desire to manage a compost pile at home.&#13;
&#13;
Collection Gaps: Municipal composting services may be non-existent or inaccessible to multi-family dwellings.&#13;
&#13;
Education: Confusion exists over what is compostable (e.g., meat vs. vegetable scraps) leading to contamination of collection bins.</problem_statement>
        <project_name>Community Organics Management and Education Platform</project_name>
        <solution_proposal><![CDATA[<h2><strong>How do you envision the ideal solution to this  problem?</strong></h2>
<p> </p>
<h3>Which ServiceNow products or capabilities would be used?</h3>
<p></p><p>Service Portal </p>
<p>Custom Table</p>
<p>Knowledge Base </p>
<p> </p>
<hr style="border-top: 3px solid #bbb;" />
<h3>Are there any technical dependencies for the proposed solution?</h3>
<p></p><p><em>Geolocation: Crucial for the map locator functionality and logistics routing.</em></p>
<p><em>QR Code Generation/Scanning: Reliance on ServiceNow Mobile App&#39;s capability for efficient, auditable tracking of resident drop-offs.</em></p>
<p> </p>
<hr style="border-top: 3px solid #bbb;" />
<h3>What challenges would you foresee in implementing this idea?</h3>
<p></p><p>Contamination Control: Ensuring residents follow the rules, as high contamination rates can ruin a batch of compost. This requires strong educational workflows.</p>
<p>Hub Liability and Incentives: Addressing any liability concerns for Hub owners and creating incentives (e.g., recognition, free compost) for them to participate.</p>
<p>Scalability: Managing the transition from a few pilot hubs to a city-wide network and handling the associated increase in logistics complexity.</p>]]></solution_proposal>
        <state>submitted</state>
        <sys_class_name>x_snc_hack4good_0_hack4good_proposal</sys_class_name>
        <sys_created_by>admin</sys_created_by>
        <sys_created_on>2025-10-29 03:39:26</sys_created_on>
        <sys_id>56eac33283b032104d3866d0deaad38b</sys_id>
        <sys_mod_count>1</sys_mod_count>
        <sys_name>Community Organics Management and Education Platform</sys_name>
        <sys_package display_value="Hack4Good Idea Submission" source="x_snc_hack4good_0">95b5d2b7938832108543b2597bba109c</sys_package>
        <sys_policy/>
        <sys_scope display_value="Hack4Good Idea Submission">95b5d2b7938832108543b2597bba109c</sys_scope>
        <sys_update_name>x_snc_hack4good_0_hack4good_proposal_56eac33283b032104d3866d0deaad38b</sys_update_name>
        <sys_updated_by>admin</sys_updated_by>
        <sys_updated_on>2025-10-29 03:39:28</sys_updated_on>
    </x_snc_hack4good_0_hack4good_proposal>
</record_update>
