<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><record_update table="x_snc_hack4good_0_hack4good_proposal">
    <x_snc_hack4good_0_hack4good_proposal action="INSERT_OR_UPDATE">
        <focus_area>cure</focus_area>
        <notes/>
        <participation>yes</participation>
        <potential_impact><![CDATA[<p>Improved healthcare coordination for millions of immigrant families managing relatives&#39; care remotely, reduced anxiety and stress for family members separated by geography during medical crises, better health outcomes through consistent advocacy and care coordination, prevention of medical emergencies through proactive monitoring and family involvement, economic benefits by avoiding emergency hospitalizations through coordinated preventive care, creation of employment opportunities for healthcare coordinators and translators in multiple countries, improved quality assurance for healthcare providers through international family feedback, enhanced communication bridging language and cultural barriers, reduced healthcare disparities for elderly patients whose advocates live abroad, and measurable improvements in patient satisfaction and family peace of mind during medical crises.</p>]]></potential_impact>
        <problem_statement>As an immigrant living in the United States, I faced a devastating situation in 2022 when my father was seriously ill in India while my mother was here helping me with my newborn baby. With no family members available to coordinate his care, I desperately called numerous healthcare providers and services, but found that many COVID-era systems were no longer operational or accessible. Immigrant families worldwide face this crisis when elderly parents or relatives need healthcare in their home countries while family caregivers live abroad. The challenges include finding reliable healthcare providers remotely, verifying quality of care from thousands of miles away, coordinating multiple services without being physically present, dealing with time zone differences for medical updates, managing payments across international banking systems, and ensuring continuity of care when emergency contacts are unavailable. Traditional healthcare systems don't account for globally distributed families, leaving vulnerable patients without proper advocacy or coordination when their primary caregivers live in different countries.</problem_statement>
        <project_name>Cross-Border Family Healthcare Coordination &amp; Remote Care Management Platform</project_name>
        <solution_proposal><![CDATA[<h2><strong>How do you envision the ideal solution to this  problem?</strong></h2>
<p> </p>
<h3>Which ServiceNow products or capabilities would be used?</h3>
<p></p><p>Having lived through the helplessness of trying to coordinate my father&#39;s care from the US while managing a newborn, I envision a ServiceNow-based platform specifically designed for cross-border family healthcare coordination. The solution includes verified provider networks in multiple countries with quality ratings and multilingual capabilities, remote family member dashboard allowing real-time monitoring of patient status and care coordination from abroad, 24/7 communication bridge with time zone-aware scheduling for family updates, trusted local advocate assignment who can physically visit patients and report back to remote family members, international payment gateway supporting multiple currencies and payment methods including US insurance coordination, care plan coordination allowing remote family input on treatment decisions with cultural sensitivity, emergency escalation system with immediate notification to family members regardless of time zones, secure document management for medical records accessible to both local providers and remote family with translation services, video consultation capabilities connecting patients local providers and remote family members, integration with international health insurance systems, and medication management with international prescription coordination. The platform bridges the gap between global families and local healthcare needs, ensuring no patient lacks advocacy simply because their family lives in another country.</p>
<p>Service Portal for remote family dashboard, Mobile App for local advocates and family members, Case Management for coordinating complex international care plans, Integration Hub for connecting healthcare systems across countries, Notification Engine for time zone-aware alerts and updates, Secure Messaging for multilingual family-provider communication, Workflow automation for care coordination and escalation procedures, Knowledge Base for international healthcare procedures and cultural guidelines, Performance Analytics for tracking care outcomes across regions, Survey functionality for provider quality ratings and family feedback, Virtual Agent for common questions in multiple languages, Field Service Management for coordinating local advocate visits</p>
<p> </p>
<p> </p>
<hr style="border-top: 3px solid #bbb;" />
<h3>Are there any technical dependencies for the proposed solution?</h3>
<p></p><p>International payment processing systems supporting multiple currencies and banking regulations, healthcare data privacy compliance across multiple countries including HIPAA and international standards, integration with healthcare provider systems in multiple countries, multilingual translation services and cultural adaptation, international telecommunications infrastructure for video consultations, time zone management systems for global coordination, mobile device compatibility in various international markets, government healthcare system integration where applicable in different countries, secure international data transmission and storage, verification systems for healthcare provider credentials across borders</p>
<p> </p>
<hr style="border-top: 3px solid #bbb;" />
<h3>What challenges would you foresee in implementing this idea?</h3>
<p></p><p>Healthcare regulatory compliance varying significantly by country and region, managing liability and insurance requirements across international boundaries, ensuring proper certification and background verification for providers in multiple countries, addressing cultural and language barriers across diverse global populations, navigating international data privacy laws and cross-border data transmission regulations, coordinating with existing healthcare systems in multiple countries without conflicts, managing quality control across distributed international provider networks, addressing varying technology infrastructure and internet connectivity across countries, ensuring 24/7 support across all time zones, balancing automation with human cultural sensitivity for international healthcare decisions, managing currency exchange rates and international payment processing fees</p>]]></solution_proposal>
        <state>submitted</state>
        <sys_class_name>x_snc_hack4good_0_hack4good_proposal</sys_class_name>
        <sys_created_by>admin</sys_created_by>
        <sys_created_on>2025-10-12 17:58:24</sys_created_on>
        <sys_id>bc6caa21832432104bb095a6feaad341</sys_id>
        <sys_mod_count>1</sys_mod_count>
        <sys_name>Cross-Border Family Healthcare Coordination &amp; Remote Care Management Platform</sys_name>
        <sys_package display_value="Hack4Good Idea Submission" source="x_snc_hack4good_0">95b5d2b7938832108543b2597bba109c</sys_package>
        <sys_policy/>
        <sys_scope display_value="Hack4Good Idea Submission">95b5d2b7938832108543b2597bba109c</sys_scope>
        <sys_update_name>x_snc_hack4good_0_hack4good_proposal_bc6caa21832432104bb095a6feaad341</sys_update_name>
        <sys_updated_by>admin</sys_updated_by>
        <sys_updated_on>2025-10-12 17:58:25</sys_updated_on>
    </x_snc_hack4good_0_hack4good_proposal>
</record_update>
