<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><record_update table="x_snc_hack4good_0_hack4good_proposal">
    <x_snc_hack4good_0_hack4good_proposal action="INSERT_OR_UPDATE">
        <focus_area>disaster</focus_area>
        <notes/>
        <participation>yes</participation>
        <potential_impact><![CDATA[<p><strong>Potential Impact of the Technology Solution:</strong><br />AidFlow would digitize and automate the coordination of disaster relief logistics, linking NGOs, local agencies, and volunteers in real-time. It ensures transparency, resource optimization, and faster delivery of help to affected regions.</p>
<p><strong>Measurable Impacts/Values:</strong><br />The solution would reduce coordination time by nearly 40%, improve equitable distribution of aid by 25%, and enhance decision-making efficiency by 50% through real-time analytics dashboards and automated task assignment.</p>]]></potential_impact>
        <problem_statement>During disasters, relief organizations struggle to coordinate supplies, volunteers, and affected communities efficiently. Manual tracking often leads to duplication of aid in some areas while other regions remain underserved.</problem_statement>
        <project_name>AidFlow – Smart Disaster Relief Coordination System</project_name>
        <solution_proposal><![CDATA[<h2><strong>How do you envision the ideal solution to this  problem?</strong></h2>
<p> </p>
<h3>Which ServiceNow products or capabilities would be used?</h3>
<p></p><p>The ideal solution would be an integrated ServiceNow app that centralizes requests for help, tracks available resources, and matches volunteer skills with needs based on geolocation data. It would include an incident response dashboard and mobile app for field agents.<br /><br />The solution would utilize ServiceNow Emergency Response Management to coordinate incidents, Flow Designer to automate relief workflows, Now Mobile to connect field volunteers, and Performance Analytics to visualize and report on real-time response metrics.</p>
<p> </p>
<hr style="border-top: 3px solid #bbb;" />
<h3>Are there any technical dependencies for the proposed solution?</h3>
<p></p><p>It would depend on GIS and Google Maps API for location tracking, cloud data storage for live updates, and SMS gateway integration to deliver alerts to users in low-connectivity zones.</p>
<p> </p>
<hr style="border-top: 3px solid #bbb;" />
<h3>What challenges would you foresee in implementing this idea?</h3>
<p></p><p>Key challenges would include integrating data from multiple NGOs using different formats, maintaining reliable connectivity in remote areas, and ensuring data privacy for individuals affected by disasters. </p>]]></solution_proposal>
        <state>submitted</state>
        <sys_class_name>x_snc_hack4good_0_hack4good_proposal</sys_class_name>
        <sys_created_by>admin</sys_created_by>
        <sys_created_on>2025-10-31 08:58:53</sys_created_on>
        <sys_id>d3ad16ebc3347210a22db90ed40131d6</sys_id>
        <sys_mod_count>1</sys_mod_count>
        <sys_name>AidFlow – Smart Disaster Relief Coordination System</sys_name>
        <sys_package display_value="Hack4Good Idea Submission" source="x_snc_hack4good_0">95b5d2b7938832108543b2597bba109c</sys_package>
        <sys_policy/>
        <sys_scope display_value="Hack4Good Idea Submission">95b5d2b7938832108543b2597bba109c</sys_scope>
        <sys_update_name>x_snc_hack4good_0_hack4good_proposal_d3ad16ebc3347210a22db90ed40131d6</sys_update_name>
        <sys_updated_by>admin</sys_updated_by>
        <sys_updated_on>2025-10-31 08:58:56</sys_updated_on>
    </x_snc_hack4good_0_hack4good_proposal>
</record_update>
